It was an age of war.
Relying on only his own skill,
one man wandered the land.
A samurai.
This man is not
a wandering samurai of today.
I don't fit in here.
-Sorry for the wait.
-You're late!
I was shopping, sorry.
Why did we have to meet here?
What do you mean?
It's easy to find.
-Why are you mad?
-I'm not mad.
Yes, you are!
I don't want to wait around where
all the young couples come to meet.
Why are you so embarrassed?
Everyone's flirting.
Should we go arm in arm?
Don't be silly.
Let's go.
-What are you doing? Let's go.
-Okay.
Slow down!
Hurry up, let's get moving.
After retiring, he lost his title
as a corporate man
and the support of his company.
Takeshi Kasumi, 60 years old.
This story
is about a normal 60-year-old man,
who is helped by a masterless samurai,
eating freely without being held back.
A gourmet fantasy.
ANNIVERSARY ODEN
Shall we go out tomorrow?
What for?
-To go shopping for something you like.
-What do you mean?
Well, you know, tomorrow is...
You mean because it's our anniversary?
We've never done anything like
that before. What's gotten into you?
Do you want to go or not?
Yes, I'll go.
Good night.
I was surprised that you wanted to
take me out all of a sudden.
Really?
Do you think
it's because you're retired now?
Maybe so.
If I think about it,
work was always...
an excuse to make little of these things.
This is the shop.
Good afternoon.
What would you like?
Let's see...
A scarf would be nice.
A scarf?
Which one?
What? Don't ask me.
You're supposed to pick one
that you think I'd be happy with.
That's what gifting is all about.
Okay, I see.
How about this?
It's a bit plain.
This one?
How about this one?
This one.
Okay.
You picked one out after all.
Thank you so much.
You're welcome.
I'm hungry.
Shall we get something to eat nearby?
This way.
Does French food sound good?
Let's go there!
Oden?
Doesn't it sound good?
Oden and a drink.
Great, oden it is!
RYU ODEN
-Cheers.
Tastes great!
What shall I order?
Here is your food.
Shochu with hot water, please.
Okay.
Did you decide?
Not yet.
They have a lot of choices.
I'm still deciding.
They do have a lot of choices.
You decided?
Go ahead and order.
Excuse me.
Yes?
Beef tendon and tomato, please.
Okay.
Have you had tomato oden before?
I've heard it's popular among women.
Did you decide?
No, still thinking.
Konjac noodles...
Here you are.
Delicious.
It's a Western take on oden.
All right, I decided.
Chef,
the daikon, konjac, and tofu fritter.
Okay.
Thanks for waiting.
Thank you.
Hot!
The daikon is exquisite.
It's absorbed the broth really well.
Delicious!
Oh, no, I forgot the mustard.
The mustard...
brings out the oden flavor,
or it could be that the oden
brings out
the mustard's flavor.
The tenderness is irresistible.
It looks fluffier than I expected.
No seasoning for the first bite.
Enjoy the flavors just as they are.
And mustard...
for the second bite.
This is the real way to enjoy oden!
Just kidding.
That's spicy!
Thank you.
Excuse me.
I'll also have the cauliflower and...
What's "anbayashi"?
It's oden from Toyama.
It's thinly sliced white konjac
with miso sauce.
I'll have that, please.
She's adventurous.
And for you, sir?
I'll have the egg...
and fish cake.
Okay.
One's character shows
when eating oden, doesn't it?
What do you mean?
After all that time,
you order the most standard items
on the menu.
Either earnest and disciplined...
or dull and uninteresting.
Hey...
why did you order that?
If you have a choice,
why not try something
you've never had before?
This miso sauce is great.
An uninteresting guy...
Is that who she sees me as?
A RISE IN MIDDLE-AGED DIVORCE RATES
No, no way.
Oh, a call from Sachiko.
I have to take this.
Hello?
That reminds me...
when was the last time we ate out?
Wow.
Here's your food.
It's been so long I can't remember.
Why do I always order egg and fish cake?
I'm just not the adventurous type.
Hey, mister...
give me a plate of whatever.
Yes, right away.
Hello!
I've got good stuff today!
How about sardines?
What's that?
This is called sea urchin.
That can't be edible!
No, you're mistaken!
Watch this.
You eat what's inside.
What is it?
Disgusting! How can you eat this?
Can you really eat that?
Sasuke...
have you eaten it?
No. Well...
-What?
-You swindler!
You're trying to sell
something you can't eat? You scoundrel!
Let me see.
God protect you!
Hey, fish seller...
You...
It's delicious.
Did you hear that?
More!
Yes, sir!
Give me one, too!
Me, too!
Here you are!
Yes, yes, yes.
It's amazing.
What are you smiling about?
Oh, nothing.
Okay.
All right.
Excuse me.
Shiroten, please!
What's shiroten?
No idea.
You ordered something new?
That's not like you.
It's nothing next to the first
person who tried sea urchin.
What are you talking about?
I...
can be adventurous, too.
For the two at the counter.
Understood!
Here you are.
This is shiroten.
This is shiroten?
I don't know what it is,
but I can't ask now.
Hot sake, please.
Oh, yeah.
What did Sachiko say?
"Happy anniversary!"
She was shocked when I said
we were eating out together.
What is it?
Thank you. Always.
What's gotten into you?
Well...
I ask for your continued support.
Thank you, too.
I ask for your support, too.
Here.
What's this?
It's a scarf.
You had this ready?
Of course!
She knows exactly when to do this.
If you're not going to eat this, let me.
I was saving that for last.
I think I like the egg most after all.
I'm going to choir.
Bye-bye.
See you later.
All right.
Subtitle translation by
Jeffrey Hales